"I am a goal-orientated, focused software engineer with 6 years of programming experience; a compassionate collaborator with high integrity and strong leadership skills."

Projects

Solidity Smart Contract Hacking and Security Exploits - May 2022

My GitHub repository presents the detailed breakdown and analysis of the security exploits in OpenZeppelin's Ethernaut Smart Contracts. Tutorial for the development of malicious contracts and smart contract attack vectors (see "Links" section).

Web3 Defi Protocol Development - Jan 2021 - Present

Developing EVM Defi protocol. Incorporating time-locking and off-chain automated control of crypto assets. Utilising Chainlink Oracles, with TLS secured APIs. (Solidity, Chainlink Keepers, Ethers, Waffle, Hardhat, Alchemy API, Chai and Slither, and React).

Latin NFTs - 1 Day Build NFT Collection - July 2022

Created and developed an original ERC721 based NFT Collection and Minting Site in one day. Next js, Solidity, Hardhat, Ethers, Chai, Waffle. (See "Links" section).

Research Blog - 8051 Microprocessor - Feb 2022

Controlling and monitoring a Keypad/Display Unit using the 8051 Microprocessor. The electronics and software of my 8051 Assembly language program (see "Links" section).

Skills

Critical Thinking & Problem-Solving. Excellent Interpersonal Skills. Leadership & Management.

Time Management & Organisation. Teamwork & Collaboration. Strong Focus, Discipline & Perseverance.

Employment History

Smart Contract Security Auditor (Freelance), WhiteLightNFT, London - July 2022

Code Review and Security Audit of Client's Solidity Smart Contracts on Avalanche. Tested functionality, uncovered exploitable vulnerabilities and refactored code fixes.

Blockchain Advisor (Freelance), KeenWorld, London - July 2022

Advised and developed creative solutions for Blockchain integration with Client's product. Documented concise technical/non-technical pitch deck for Investors/Users.

Web3 Developer (Freelance), Handbag Clinic, London - May 2022 - Jun 2022

Designed and developed architecture for 'Minting' and 'Marketplace' smart contracts for the issuance of 'proof of authenticity' NFT certificates.

(Polygon, IPFS, Solidity, Hardhat, Ethers js, Alchemy) (React js for Mint/Transfer UI).

Database Developer (Freelance), Wivey Cares Charity, Wiveliscombe - Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

Developed a UI WebApp for the management of the charity's data. Engineered, formatted, and migrated legacy data (Microsoft PowerApps & Dataverse, VBA, SQL).

Software Developer (Intern), aCommerse Co, Bangkok - Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

Automated historic data from the online marketplace for analysis. Created interactive web UI for the process using: Django, Python, REST API's, SQL, data engineering.

Data Engineer (Freelance), Intracon Inspection Services, Taunton - Aug 2019 - Nov 2019

Automated/migrated historic data from legacy .asp to a Word-Press-based site (SQL, VBA Excel data engineering, data import and mapping to create data visualisation).

Extra-curricular Activities

President of Poker Society, Queen Mary University, London - Sep 2021 - Present

Management of society operations; organisation of social events, budgeting, generating society income, and marketing to expand the society's reach.

Exercising leadership, management, organization, forward-thinking, marketing, and economic skills. Teaching and practising poker's beneficial psychology/strategy.

Education

BEng Robotics Engineering, Queen Mary University, London - Sep 2020 - Present

Achieved Second-Year average of 79% and First-Year average of 70%. Notable Modules inc. Design/Build Robotics Project, OOP, C, and Procedural Programming. Predicted to graduate with First Class Honours in July 2024.

3 A-Levels, Richard Huish Sixth Form College, Taunton - Sep 2017 – Jul 2019

Maths (A), Physics (B), Computer Science (B)

10 GCSEs, Kingsmead Community School, Wiveliscombe - Sep 2012 - Jul 2017 6A's, 3B's, 1C - incl. Maths (B), Physics (A), Chemistry (A)

Charles Benson

DEFI & WEB3 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

SE1 6RW. London **United Kingdom** 07450059035 charliejrbenson@gmail.com

Links

GitHub LinkedIn

Twitter

Latin NFT Collection Smart Contract Hacking

Technology Research Blog

Technical Skills

Python, JavaScript, Ethereum EVM & Solidity, Java, OOP, C,

Assembly Lang, Git, SQL, Docker,

HTML & CSS, React

Hobbies

Web3 & Defi Development Passionate to progress the Web3, Blockchain, and Defi industries.

Completion of the OZ Ethernaut Smart Contract Hacking Challenges. Attended Chainlink Spring 2021 Hackathon and London Coin Bureau Conference 2022.

Hardware

Constructed, wired, and programmed a full-scale UAV drone, aged twelve. Built high-performance PCs since the age of fourteen.

Music

Avid guitar player and music theorist since 2018.

Sport

Parkour - practised since the age of eleven, travelling the UK to various competitions and challenges.

Karate – achieving blackbelt at the age of fifteen.

Diving - student of the Tom Daley High Diving Academy.

Leena Chanvirach, aCommerse Co, Regional Head of Data & Analytics - leena@acommerce.asia

Piers Bennett, aCommerse Co, CFO piers@acommerce.asia